

nikita-zhidkov-5b6bb5128/

## Summary.

I'm a digital nomad (currently in Indonesia, Bali). Current Machine Learning Engineer at AdTech company PropellerAds. 3+ years experience specializing in the machine learning and 4+ years experience specializing in full stack development. I love building established development processes in a team and interacting with the business team to improve the product. Interested in startups and pet projects.

## Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

**PropellerAds** Remote

ML ENGINEER Apr. 2021 - now

- Create smart billing advertising strategies: billing by the click that equal billing by conversion
- Introduce approach of using text and image additional advertising information like a result increases revenue by 3%
- Create a full pipeline for offline testing and model validation
- · Calibrated ML models and as a result make a billing fair
- Use monitoring environment(Grafana) which gathers system metrics (model learning time, data quality, outlier detection)
- Technology: LogReg, FFM, DeepFM, Airflow, Vertica, Streamlit, Docker

**EPAM Systems** Saint Petersburg, Russia

ML ENGINEER

- Nov. 2019 Apr. 2021
- Build from zero to production ready reccomendation system • Built CI/CD pipelines on Github Actions and Docker

**EPAM Systems** Saint Petersburg, Russia

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Optimize website speed loading on 300%
- Introduce SEO best practices that increase organic traffic x2
- Technology: AngularJS, Crownpeak CMS

Startups \_\_\_\_\_

**Onlytips** Remote CO-FOUNDER & CTO Nov. 2021 - now

• Managed teams of 3 employees and monitored projects to ensure progress.

- · Led the development from the beginning and created a service consistent with the latest technology and stable operation
- Technologies: React, Firebase, Payu (payment system)

**Click Clothes** Remote

CO-FOUNDER & CTO Dec. 2020 - Oct. 2021

- Managed teams of 2 employees and monitored projects to ensure progress.
- Implement recommendation system that increase "Liked" items from 10% to 50% for user
- Technologies: Django, PostgreSQL, Redis, Celery,

## Education

**Saratov State University** Saratov, Russia

BACHELOR OF INFORMATICS AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING

Sep. 2014 - May. 2019

Dec. 2015 - Nov. 2019